SAMIA SOUDAMINI SENZUTI

Software Engineer | Web Developer | Cloud Solutions

@ samiasoudamini@gmail.com https://github.com/samiaSejuti ****0410794849

ttps://www.linkedin.com/in/samia-senzuti-599b19147/

https://samiasejuti.github.io/portfolio/

Melbourne, VIC

SUMMARY

Passionate software engineer with 1 year+ of experience in web application development, data analysis, cloud technologies, Android IOS development and UI/UX design. A very creative, fast learner, and result-oriented: I try to do every work as perfect as possible.

EXPERIENCE

Associate Instructor, Faculty of IT

Monash University 05/2023 - Present Clayton, VIC

- Guide students in Internet Application Development using the MVC design pattern, focusing on robust web applications with ASP.NET and ASP.NET Core.
- Teach Bootstrap for UI/UX design, enabling students to create visually appealing and responsive websites.
- SQL database usage and management, preparing students for complex data handling.
- Teach deployment and management of web applications on Microsoft Azure cloud.

Industry Experience

MONASH UNIVERSITY & TELSTRA GROUP LTD.

07/2023 - 10/2023 Website: https://iteration3.univerze.me/

- Developed a platform with a five-member, diverse IT team to assist international students in settling in Melbourne
- Technologies Used: Next.js, React, Material-UI (MUI), DaisyUI, Tailwind CSS, MySQL, Vercel, Github

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Associate Instructor, Data Fluency

Monash University

06/2022 - Present

- · Instruct Python and R programming for data exploration, cleaning, and interpretation, ensuring data readiness.
- Provide data visualization training using Python, R, MS Power BI, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript D3 library.
- Use R Shiny for the development of interactive web applications

Business Executive

Business Automation Ltd.

11/2020 - 02/2021

Managed IT products and streamlined help desk processes across 54 countries in the African region

IT Business Analyst

Apex Property Ltd.

09/2019 - 03/2020

- Developed and executed sales proposals while overseeing U.S. clients and contractors to ensure adherence to technical and business standards.
- Conducted onboarding sessions for new hires and developed training materials to enhance team skills.

CERTIFICATION

The Complete 2024 Web Development Bootcamp

UDEMY

Developed full-stack websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Bootstrap, React, and PostgreSQL.

EDUCATION

Masters in Information Technology

Monash University

Clayton, VIC 03/2021 - 12/2023

SKILLS

Programming Languages

Java	Python	C#	HTML	CSS	JS
ASP. NET .NET Core		Core	AWS	React.js	
Next.js	Azure	_			

Databases

SQL	NoSQL-Mongodb	PostgreSQL	
Fireba	se		

PROJECTS

NexaScan: Hospital CT scan scheduling platform

Technologies Used: C#, ASP.NET 7, Github, Bootstrap, MySQL

The platform features secure authentication, enabling patients to select doctors, schedule appointments, rate practitioners, and write public reviews. Additionally, administrators have the capability to send detailed reports to patients, including attachments.

Containerized Image Detection and Serverless Cloud Storage

Technologies Used: Python, YOLOv3-tiny, OpenCV-Python, Flask, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS (Lambda, S3, API Gateway, DynamoDB, Cognito, IAM)

A toll service that captures car number plates at gates, stores images in S3 bucket, uses Python to detect numbers, retrieves driver details from DynamoDB, and notifies drivers.

Android goal setting app

Technologies Used: Java, Firebase, API, Mapbox

Developed an Android app that allows users to authenticate, set goals, visualize their progress on maps, and track goal achievement.